(Watch on KonFlix.vip)
Angelito D. Pinagpala!
BEST IN SCIENCE
JOSE RIZAL AWARD
BEST IN FILIPINO
MOST CREATIVE THINKER
But you are not
the main character of this story.
Because the real main character
of this story
-is this guy.
-A toast for my brother!
He's Michael D. Pinagpala.
-Angelito!
-Or better known as Mikoy.
…and of course, delicious.
Just get some more. There's still plenty.
One more.
The hope of the Pinagpala family!
The most blessed among the Pinagpala!
The one who will lift
our family out of hardship!
And
the one who will raise the banner
of the Pinagpala family.
And the one who will change the rotten
and corrupt government system!
The one who will
bring down the ruling class!
The one who will jail the corrupt
and those shameless bas--
Hey!
You talk too much!
Your brother might get red-tagged!
Anyway, on this day, we will celebrate.
For my most beloved brother.
This is my promise.
Angelito, I will do everything.
I will sacrifice everything.
Just to make your dream come true.
Because the fulfillment
of my brother's dream
is the fulfillment of the dream
of our entire family!
BEAR AND BEER
Look at Mom and Dad.
They're still so sweet with each other.
Looks like they even plan
to have another after us.
But you know, Mikoy.
That's what you should dream about.
Like Mom.
-Like Mom how?
-Yes.
Someone you'll spend your life with.
Someone you'll love.
Someone who will love you unconditionally.
You're not a kid anymore.
You should start settling down.
Just wait, if you
end up growing old alone.
Wow, huh!
The way you talk, it's like you're
the older brother between us.
Besides, that's not even on my mind.
All that love stuff!
Jeez!
The only thing on my mind
is for you to finish your studies.
Bro, I was thinking…
I don't really need to study at PU.
And now, we are going
to watch a flashback.
Flashback, here we go.
Whoo!
What is it, bro?
What is it?
I got a scholarship in Manila!
This is the beginning of your brother
becoming big time.
Scholarship?!
You're really my idol, bro!
You have to find a way!
You need to get our money back!
Tess, do you think I don't want
to get our money back?
Those scammers ran away with it!
What about our business?
What about our house?
That was the moment
he had to set aside his dreams.
That was the moment he had to become
a pillar for his own family.
Studying in Manila these days is no joke.
Hey, Angelito!
Don't end up like me, okay?
You will continue going to Manila!
Don't let the chance to have
a good life pass you by.
By hook or by crook,
you will finish college.
I'll take care of it.
I'll find a way.
-There! Just look at the color of this!
-Angge, come on.
-Hurry up.
-It's so beautiful!
There! Here, Angge.
Fe…
Put a tag on this.
-Where's the one for the captain?
-Here it is.
The other one? Is it there already?
Okay, good, good.
Mikoy! Mikoy!
Son!
Mikoy! Come here. Take this with you.
Please deliver this
to the captain in Tumana.
Oh, Mother!
-Go on! Go deliver that! Be careful!
-Okay!
-Oops! Oops!
-Oh, bro?
Well! No hangover, huh!
Yes, I'm a grown man now.
Nice!
Fe, put a tag on these, okay?
-Dad!
-Hey!
Are you heading out? Boom!
-One, two, three!
-Where should we put it?
Oh!
-Tie!
-Oh, tie!
-Tomorrow again!
-Boom! Boom! Boom!
PINAGPALA
SPECIAL OMELET
-Take care, son!
-Yes, Mom!
Their business is earning well.
But it's enough
for their household expenses.
Just enough for three meals a day
and payment for debts.
Mikoy knows that in order for him
to send his brother to Manila,
he needs to find other side hustles.
How many ways are there
for us to earn money?
One is to become a district engineer.
Second, to win a lottery.
Ahh!
Ouch!
My goodness!
Or third,
to go overseas and to work abroad.
The same option taken by millions
of our fellow countrymen.
To look for better work abroad.
To leave the country!
To go overseas for the economy!
Jakub!
Yes, ma'am? You need anything?
Oh, I'm so sorry. I don't understand.
I don't speak French.
Why didn't you laugh?
Hey. Oh?
There she is.
Ma'am Beautiful!
Ma'am Beautiful?
Hey!
-Sorry! I'm sorry.
-Give me money!
Go to hell.
Ouch!
That will hurt.
Mommy!
Ouch!
That was close.
Huh?
No…
-You're Filipino, right?
-understand.
Huh?
Are you Filipino, too?
There's a Filipino here, too.
Wait. Who were those guys?
They're assholes!
Good thing you came, right?
They got scared of you.
Your shouting scared them off.
Thank you, my fellow countryman.
It's really only Filipinos
who help other Filipinos, right?
Uhm…
And she always tells me
about her life in Pampanga.
What are you doing here?
Did you follow me?
By the way…
Yes!
I followed you.
I'll return your money.
Huh?
Yes, I left that for you. It's my tip.
Tip?
All of that?
This is equivalent
to three months of my salary.
Do you need anything?
Excuse me, madam?
-I will handle this.
-That's terrible
Do you even have any idea
what she was saying to you?
No.
But you don't need to understand.
From their tone,
you can tell something bad
is coming out of their mouth.
And that's okay.
I'm used to it, anyway.
Huh?
No!
Ma'am, I'm not thinking that way.
Also, it's not about the race.
There are still some you will encounter…
Uhm…
Assholes.
Chiara.
Uh…
Mikoy!
Michael, actually.
Michael D. Pinagpala.
Oh, sorry.
Uh, thank you, but I apologize.
I really can't accept this.
This is way over the top.
Huh?
Deal?
Unless you're afraid of our beer.
They say that beer here in Prague
is made for only real men.
Oh! Hey!
It's not that I'm bragging, ma'am.
But this is the national drinker
of the Philippines.
When it comes to beer,
I am not intimidated.
Then, it's a deal?
Okay! Sure!
It's a deal!
Thank you, Mikoy! This is way too much!
Wait a minute.
Son, are you sure about this?
Because it seems you gave us too much.
Yes, Mom!
Are you still eating there?
It seems like you sent your entire salary.
No, Mom. That's an extra.
Because the other day,
a customer left a really big tip.
Seriously, it's over the top!
I'd spend it anyway.
So I just sent it to you.
Why would they give you such a big tip?
Did you give
a "happy ending"?
What "happy ending" are you talking about?
Actually, me too, bro.
I don't need the extra money.
You don't need
to send me money next month.
Why, though?
You already gave me too much.
And you know what?
I also found a side job here, bro.
You might get tired there.
You might lose focus on your studies.
I agree with your brother!
No, Mom.
I can manage my load, anyway!
Son, instead of doing a part-time job,
just go hang out.
You're so funny, Dad.
He should have fun sometime.
Have a little drink if you have time.
That's what I'm saying…
You always do that!
Dad has a point too, Mom.
Oh, you too!
You're tolerating
your Dad's foolish behavior!
Mom, what I meant is,
it's good that Angelito
can still hang out sometimes.
He only gets to go to college once.
Then why don't you follow
your own advice, bro?
I think you're the one who needs to relax.
You seem overworked in Prague.
What?
I'm overworked?
No!
I have work-life balance here, kid!
I'm partying here all the time.
Maybe you're always with girls?
Oh, Dad!
My looks are definitely a hit
with these Czech girls.
You'll be surprised.
When I come home,
you'll have three grandchildren already.
Crazy!
So annoying.
Just kidding!
But you know, my children,
Mikoy and Angelito,
your dad and I really miss you.
Same here, Mom and Dad.
I really miss you.
Even you, Angelito.
But don't worry.
I'm really okay here.
Just hang in there, Mom.
I'll be able to come home soon.
But Mikoy and Angelito, don't ever forget.
No matter what happens,
your mom and I are always here.
I love you, Mom!
I love you, Dad!
Oh my! It's so cold.
You take ten kilos for the price of eight.
I'll give you extra potatoes.
What are you doing here?
Why? Are you the only one allowed
to roam around the city of Prague?
Why did he leave me?
He's unbelievable.
They probably noticed
that I really need a friend right now.
Are you okay?
Is there a problem?
Hmm…
Then, I saw you.
I remembered our deal.
Are you good?
Uh…
Where do you plan to go?
To the zoo?
To the zoo?!
Yes.
I want to see a hippopotamus.
Hippopotamus?
There!
So that's the hippo!
Yes.
He's really good!
It's tasty.
Hits hard.
I can really feel it in my stomach.
After this shot,
I'll introduce you to the tiger.
Oh!
Rawr!
Can you still handle it?
This tiger is really strong.
But I can still handle it.
Since you can still manage,
then let's go big!
Briii!
Wow!
But I can still handle it!
Is this the best that Prague can offer?
Wait for it. There's more.
Oh!
That one?!
Is that the giraffe?
It became a snack.
Aren't you funny?
Oh?
Where's the giraffe?
There you go.
That's the giraffe!
Long neck.
It's yummy!
How's the heavy drinker?
It seems you can't handle
drinking here in Prague.
Do you want me
to take you to the hospital?
Thank you!
You know what?
You're probably
the biggest mystery in life.
After all the drinks we had earlier,
why does alcohol seem
to have no effect on you?
Huh?
For someone that small,
where did you put all that beer?
I don't know if you're
complimenting or insulting me.
But thank you.
Thank you for drinking with me.
Actually,
I should be the one thanking you.
Because of you,
I got to see the other side of Prague.
I've just been going between home
and work ever since I got here.
So I had no idea
that there's a unique zoo here in Prague.
Also, I even saw
a hippopotamus.
Right?
You know,
you should give yourself more time.
I want to,
but I came here to work.
For my family.
So I'm not thinking
about myself now.
I'm thinking about them first.
Yes. That's how it should be.
Sometimes it's really annoying, huh?
Why were we born into this world
That's why sometimes
it feels so good to run away
from responsibilities.
Is that why you're here?
Hmm?
You chose to drink with someone
you don't really know.
Because you're running
away from something?
Hmm…
Am I really that easy to read?
Papa is frustrated because
he wants me to run the family business.
I don't want to be stuck here
running a family business
that has nothing to do with me.
There's nothing wrong
unless you try, right?
You'll never know.
Everything might turn out okay.
If you run away from them,
will it make you happy?
Could you
just turn your back
on the people you love?
Could you live
if you never see your family again?
Family is complicated.
But they're still our family.
And we will still love them.
No matter how hard it gets.
No matter how complicated
the situation is.
Because for me,
that's what it means to be a real family.
You can't hold your drinks well, but…
I hope so.
Because
I have nothing to be proud of in my life.
So, as much as I can,
I'll just try to be a good person.
Like you.
Right?